Joonas Hiltunen

+358 44 9890011 | joonas@jontzi.com | joonashiltunen.fi | linkedin.com/in/joohiltunen

Profile

I am a versatile full-stack software developer with around five years of comprehensive experience in various projects, from small one-person apps to extensive enterprise software. I excel in C# and JS/TS-based projects while being flexible and quickly grasping new technologies as required. In the future, I am interested in taking on a more significant role in some larger projects and in expanding my expertise in cloud technologies.

Experience

Vincit Oyj

Mar. 2022 – Present

Software Developer

I am working as part of a team developing a completely new booking engine and a website for a large Finnish hotel chain. The engine will have integrations with multiple platforms to manage reservations made through multiple channels.

- Worked on the booking engine which is built with .NET/C#
- Integrations with multiple other systems, such as SmartHotel and Oracle Opera

Previously, I worked with a team planning, researching, and developing proof-of-concept software for a client in the esports industry.

- Researching and utilising multiple different e-sports data feed APIs
- The software will utilise machine learning and generative AI

I developed Vincit's internal payroller software, which our salary team uses to calculate the correct bonuses, provisions, and other benefits for workers.

• Integrations with multiple other systems used by the salary team

I worked as a consultant for a well-known company in the energy sector, developing a customer information system used by many of Finland's largest energy companies.

- Worked on the reporting module of the customer's flagship CIS product
- Worked on modifying the module for a new foreign market
- Developed a cutting-edge reporting microservice for a customer's new software product

NomiCam Oy (Now part of Amazon Ring) Software Developer, Sept. 2020 – Feb. 2022 May 2019 – Feb. 2022

- Wrote and maintained software for NomiCam's Dynamic
- Implemented improvements and bugfixes for NomiCam's MIP
- Developed plugins for NomiCam's MIP software using C#

Junior Software Developer, Sept. 2019 – Aug. 2022

- Implement CI pipeline for NomiCam's MIP software
- Implemented improvements and bugfixes for NomiCam's MIP
- Developed plugins for NomiCam's MIP software using C#
- Build a remote control for an industrial robot using .NET Core

Software Developer Trainee, May 2019 - Aug. 2019

- Developed plugins for NomiCam's MIP software using C#
- Wrote user documentation for MIP plugins

Technical Skills

Languages: C#, JavaScript, TypeScript, SQL (PostgreSQL), Java, C++, HTML, CSS

Frameworks: .NET Core, ASP.NET, React, Node.js, Next.js, Tailwind CSS

Developer Tools: Git, Docker, Terraform, Kubernetes, Visual Studio, CI/CD, Jest, Azure DevOps, GitHub Actions

Cloud Platforms: AWS, Azure, Vercel

Education

Tampere University

Sept. 2022 – May 2024 (est.)

Master of Science in Technology Major: Software, Web, and Cloud

Thesis: Comparison of cloud platforms for hosting microservices

Credits: 117/120

Tampere University / Tampere University of Technology

Aug. 2018 - Sept. 2022

Bachelor of Science in Technology Major: Software Engineering

Thesis: Adding continuous delivery to a legacy software

Languages skills

Finnish: Native Proficiency

English: Full Professional Proficiency **Swedish:** Elementary Proficiency

Other Projects

Homepage | React, Node.js, Next.js, TypeScript, Tailwind CSS, Vercel | joonashiltunen.fi

- A new personal website for myself
- Build using Next.js with TypeScript and Tailwind CSS
- Deployed using Vercel

Flight randomizer | React, Node.js, Next.js, TypeScript, Chakra UI, Vercel | flights.jontzi.com

- A simple tool for selecting a random flight from an airport
- Created using Next.js with TypeScript and Chakra UI library
- Utilises data from FlightRadar24 APIs for finding airports and flights
- Deployed using Vercel

Get a Room! | React, Node.js, TypeScript, MUI, Google Cloud, Docker | getaroom.vincit.com

- A progressive web app for booking a meeting room on the fly
- Developed as part of a university course as part of a team
- Utilises Google Workspace and Google Calendar APIs
- Explicitly designed for Vincit but can be deployed for any organisation using Google Calendar
- Deployed to Google Cloud Run